<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjamin Ortiz</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Benjamin Ortiz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 10:21:31 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 10:21:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Ben. Nice to meet you.
I am a full-stack developer at Blue Bottle Coffee. In addition, I have done management, product design, and systems administration.
Becoming a better teacher is extremely important to me. I&amp;rsquo;d love to help you in any way I can.
I create things (furniture, ceramics, video games, etc.) in my free time. You might catch me live streaming my current project.
github // linkedin // dev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching with Questions</title>
      <link>/posts/teaching-with-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 16:59:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/teaching-with-questions/</guid>
      <description>Long ago, in my early days of junior high AVID, I was taught to teach and lead by asking questions. The most effective way to get a person to understand a concept is to guide them to the conclusion with questions. This way, the learn the concept for themselves.
For example, today I was trying to teach one of my interns how a form tag worked in HTML. She was hung up on it needing to be next to the button that would submit the form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Multiple Submissions</title>
      <link>/posts/preventing-multiple-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 16:59:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/preventing-multiple-submissions/</guid>
      <description>I have a gem that has been giving me trouble lately. It saved me countless hours of dev time upfront, but is beginning to cause me problems now that I want to extend it. I learned quickly how to clone and edit a gem locally using the gem gem_name, path: &#39;path/to/local/gem&#39;, to get the changes I personally needed.
The difficulty came when, for some yet inexplicable reason, it was causing duplicate calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Rails&#39; main_app</title>
      <link>/posts/main-app-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 00:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/main-app-paths/</guid>
      <description>My third rails engine added to OppSites brought up some interesting challenges. The first two I installed, from Instacart&amp;rsquo;s Open Source repository, were completely self contained in their views. This third one, user_impersonate2, was my first experience with an engine that embedded itself within my own layouts.
While that behavior was necessary and useful, it was surprising when I started getting errors saying previously working path helpers were undefined.
It turns out, there is some sort of main_app that can be appended to a path helper to tell it to use the helper in the context of the &amp;ldquo;main app&amp;rdquo; instead of the engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Lost Commits</title>
      <link>/posts/finding-lost-commits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 16:59:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/finding-lost-commits/</guid>
      <description>In the process of rebasing with preserving a merge commit (git rebase -i -p base_branch), I somehow managed to lose two commits I was trying to squash together.
To find the lost commits, I tried to use a combination of git commands. First, I tried using git fsck --lost-found which returned a list of commits that were &amp;ldquo;dangling&amp;rdquo;. I have no idea how these specific commits got lost to time, but now they were found.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>